# Susmitha Bojja

## Test Lead

Address Hyderabad, India 500032

**Phone** 9700069523

E-mail bsusmitha91@gmail.com

Over **7.1 years** of experience in Software Quality Assurance, API testing, for **Web** and Mobile application testing in client/server and web-based applications fluently in variant domains. Expertise in Manual application testing for both web and Mobile.

## **Technical Profile**

- Expertise in Manual application testing for both web and Mobile
- Expertise in API Testing using Postman/ SOAP UI/Swagger
- Experience in API performance testing using Jmeter
- Working knowledge on API automation using AccelQ tool
- Good working knowledge in all types of functional, API, GUI testing
- Knowledge on TestNg framework, Maven Project management tool
- Knowledge on Cucumber framework using Selenium
- Expertise in System, Integration and usability testing of the applications
- Experienced in developing high level Test scenarios, Test cases, and reporting test defects
- Experience in executing SQL, MY SQL, SAP queries as a part of the backend testing
- Maintaining the Traceability Matrix, Status report related to project
- Interaction with the Stakeholders as part of implementing and reviewing of
- requirements
- Troubleshooting the issues and finding the defects, classifying and reporting bugs through Defect Tracking system and involved/conducted defect triage
- Expert in using MTM, Team Foundation Server, Qmetry as a repository for maintaining test cases, execution, defect tracking
- Possess strong analytical and communication skills
- Manages and directs overall project team activities and monitors progress, including capacity planning and mentoring staff, and internal process improvement activity
- Expertise in Integration testing. Few ATS are Bullhorn, WorkDay, ADPRM, Taleo
- Business, People fluent, SAP success factory, JobDiva, Job Adder, LOOP, Searcher, Smart Recruiter, Workable, Brassring
- Involved in Task Creation, Task Estimation, Task Distribution, Task Prioritization and Communication among team members

## **Work History**

2022-04- Test Lead

2023-01 Allegis Services (India) Pvt. Ltd(TEKsystems Ind), Hyderabad

Client: Deloitte Swift

Test Management Tool: ADO(TFS)

Database: SAP HR

DTE is a Timesheet web application, used to track the daily working hours and other details of the practitioner. I worked for South East Asia(SEA) countries. Total 10 countries come under SEA.

## Responsibilities:

- Worked on data setup with the security and other teams
- Grooming new joiners
- Involved in test case review, test execution in different environments. Supported UAT and involved in bridge calls, defect calls during ITC1 and worked on tickets
- Optimized test cases to maximize success of manual software testing
- Experienced in executing different Tcodes and tables in SAP
- Performed exploratory testing

## 2021-02- Senior Software Test Engineer

2022-04 Allegis Services (India) Pvt. Ltd (TEKsystems India), Hyderabad

### GIAS Transaction -Thriven(Client: Deloitte):

Duration: Nov 2021 to April 2022

Test Management Tool: Jira, Qmetry

Database : SQL Server Domain : Insurance

#### **Description:**

Thrivent is a financial service organization which provides financial advice, insurance, banking service etc. GIAS is an web application of insurance domain. This application worked on Whole Life, Universal Life and Variable Universal Life, Variable Annuity contracts test scenario creation and on execution of Death Claims, Loan Payments, Benefit Change and so on.

## Non GIAS BRE Rules -Thrivent (Client - Deloitte):

Duration: May 2021 to Oct 2021

Test Management Tool: Jira, Qmetry

Automation tool: AccelQ

Database : SQL Server Domain : Insurance

#### **Description:**

Thrivent is a financial service organization which provides financial advice, insurance, banking service etc. This project is related to insurance and it involves the generation of different types of letters i.e, batch and interactive letters based on the BRE rules engine. APIs are used to integrate BRE rules. BRE rules are the specifications which indicate the letter details, delivery preferences and so on.

## Responsibilities:

- BRE requirement analysis
- API test case design, API test execution using Postman and SQL Server API automation test scripts creation in AccelQ tool
- Involved in API automation documentation

## Supervisor Portal-Spirit Aerosystems (Deloitte):

Duration : Feb 2021 to May 2021 Test Management Tool : Jira, TestRail

Database: SQL Server

Domain: Aerospace Industry

#### **Description:**

Spirit Aerosystems Inc, a global aircraft manufacturer. Supervisor Portal is the web application used in Tablets to monitor the airplane design and manufacturing process progress. Portal has the different types of views to track the manufacture status i.e, Views, Metrics, Areas status and are integrated to application using APIs.

#### Responsibilities:

- Involving in GUI, Functional, Regression test case design and test execution
- Involved/conducted defect triage

## 2017-01- Senior Software Test Engineer

2021-02 Spectraforce Technologies India Pvt. Ltd., Hyderabad

## Integrations and API (Leoforce):

Duration: Dec 2019 to Feb 2021 Test Management Tool: TFS

#### **Description:**

Leoforce is an ATS. Arya supports an open API platform and is integrated with third party Applicant Tracking Systems (ATS), Candidate Relationship Management tools (CRM), Recruitment Marketing, Job Boards, and candidate profile enrichment providers.

#### Responsibilities:

- Lead API testing for entire application
- Lead team of 4 members
- Conducting Scrum meetings
- As a lead responsibility managing team, assigning tasks, attending team meeting, preparing test plans, preparing test strategy, reviewing test cases and bug reports, understanding requirement of project, and discussing them with team Worked with Stakeholders/Product owners/Scrum Master to ensure requirement coverage
- Prepared API documentation
- Regular trainings provided for new joiners and also existing employees on latest updates of project/product
- Conducting one on one meeting for individuals in team

## Arya (Leoforce):

Duration: Jan 2017 to Nov 2019

Role: Test Engineer/ Manual Tester

Test Management Tool: TFS, MTM

## Responsibilities:

- Provided new implementation thoughts to stakeholders and those are implemented.
   Involved in Task Creation, Task Estimation, Task Distribution, Task Prioritization and
   Communication among team members
- API execution in Swagger
- Guided on API test case design to peers and juniors
- Worked on APIs analysis, test case design.
- API execution in REST API

- Working with marketing team for content management
- Worked on GDPR and BLS data validations

## 2015-12- Test Engineer

2016-12 W3SoftTech, Hyderabad

#### Leoforce ATS:

## **Client - Spectraforce Technologies**

Duration: Dec 2015 to Dec 2016 Role: Test Engineer/ Manual Tester Test Management Tool: MTM.

### **Description:**

Arya is the team's personal sourcing assistant, helping them find and engage the best candidates.

#### Responsibilities:

- Worked on test case design
- Executed smoke and regression testing
- Involving in GUI, Functional, Regression testing
- Detecting, Classifying and Reporting Bugs through Defect Tracking system Involved/conducted defect triage

## **Education**

# 2009- Bachelor of Technology: Electrical And Electronics Engineering

2013 Kakatiya Institute of Technology And Science - Warangal